Marisa Denaro

Senior Web Developer - ATMI

Danbury, CT - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Marisa-Denaro/9c0bd9f3b15a3e1f

I am a professional lead developer with deep expertise and proven success in full lifecycle software development projects. I am recognized by Microsoft and hold many advanced certifications in key programming and database technologies. Through my technical excellence and business consulting experience I created solutions that achieve challenging business goals that bridge the gap between business vision and real-world technologies. Expertise in project management, analysis and development skills, along with self-direction, makes me an exceptional resource in several diverse roles.

Technology Experiences

- Multithreaded Programming
 E-Commerce Platforms
 Custom SharePoint Web Parts/Workflows
- Scientific Applications Mobile Applications Inventory Applications
- Intranet/Extranet Applications A/R Applications MEDIC Integration Applications
- 3rd-Party Systems Integration COM+ Services Quality & Financial Reporting
- Technical Documentation A/P Applications Project Management Reporting & Planning
- Content Management Invoice Applications Purchase Order Applications

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Web Developer

ATMI - Danbury, CT - March 2008 to Present

Worked with R&D to understand their business problems and delivered the appropriate custom .Net enterprise solution to facilitate a scientific work load monitoring system; "Technical Request System" (TRS). Authenticating with Active Directory, the system comprises features of global processes, coordination of worldwide workload from one lab to another and prioritization of the scientific instruments. Acting as a Project Manager exercising SDLC methodology, an Architect utilizing my knowledge of several Design Patterns (Singleton & Provider and Adapter) and a Developer by engineering a complete custom front-end application via ASP.Net server controls along with producing custom reusable user controls and classes that extended functionality to the Information Technology Platform (TIP) and Accelyrs Electronic Notebook (ELN) systems.

- Designed and developed a custom N-Tier ASP.Net/Oracle enterprise application; "Sales Funnel". Its purpose was to streamline the major part of the sales forecasting activities carried out within the company; bringing about the most significant improvements in the business process by tracking worldwide opportunities, risk, assumptions and broadcasting highlighted information through crystal reports and dashboards. Engineered a complete custom front-end web application by means of reiterating my Project Manager, Architect and Developer roles, in conjunction with exercising Design Patterns like Repository and UML diagrams.
- Develop Business logic layer to ensure solid, scalable, robust solutions by implementing Object Oriented Programming languages (OOPS) CONCEPTS abstraction, encapsulation, inheritance, polymorphism in C#.
- Utilizing .Net SharePoint object library to develop applications comprising of custom SharePoint Lists, web parts, workflows and task lists:
- o KBM application that Tracks Six Sigma certifications, projects and savings.
- o Business Performance Excellence (BPE) Metrics Application to tracks the stage of the product lifecycle our products fall under.
- o Employee Audit application integrates across multi-platforms (HR system/Workday, SQL, Oracle and SharePoint); permitting the compliance officer to assure that all employees have the correct provisions across

all systems by means of retrieving the employee's credentials in Active Directory and outputting the merged information in a custom built .Net SharePoint List.

- Embedded .Net components into the Accelyrs Electronic Notebook software utilizing Python, XML and .Net Web Services fetching data from numerous internal multi-platform systems; Wafer Inventory SharePoint List, SQL chemical inventory and Oracle Customer & Project Code information.
- Architected and implemented a quality control report for the engineers, utilizing the .NET PowerPoint addon that pulls data from oracle and generates statistical information and custom control charts for our external customers.
- Reiterating my Project Manager, Architect and Developer roles, engineered a .NET custom scorecard application that rates customer support based on surveys, response time, ticket failures, reopen tickets etc. The dashboard highlights the technicians YTD average, which the managers uses to evenly assign work load and address bottlenecks.
- Architected and implemented a windows service to extract specific metrics information by rendering XML data from log files and store the entries in a centralized SQL database. Later, the metrics data would be extracted from the database and transformed via XSLT into the schema specified by the analyst to validate the experimental results.
- Responsible for Adding/changing/removing users and user permissions, adding permissions for users on various sites, updating content, changing navigation, creating/modifying/restoring SharePoint Portal Sites and Windows SharePoint Services sites.
- Currently utilizing Windows Phone OS 8.1 and LINQ to engineer a mobile application that allows the analyst to signoff their experimental runs, via their window phones. Will be expanding the prototype by remodelling the same window forms via the HTML5 toolkit for ASP.NET MVC to establish cross platforms phone architecture.

Consultant

William B Meyers - Bridgeport, CT - December 2007 to February 2008

Prudential Annuities engaged Fosdick Corporation to provide its literature fulfillment services, which introduced a need of an e-commerce web-based order system that integrates with their current Epiphany system. The order system contained features like online ordering, shopping cart, promotions & allocations, shipment tracking, order history and administrative functions maintain user security level activity and reporting.

E-Business Consultant/ Software Architect/Web Developer

Optimum Systems, Inc - Danbury, CT - June 2000 to November 2007

Developed brand-new e-commerce .NET websites;

- o JMClipper website comprises consumer online ordering, shopping cart, payment gateway and custom ordering of parts utilizing the open source AutoCAD/.Net.
- o A membership registration application for the YMCA's comprising of payment of subscriptions.
- o A global management website called "ePAR-Project Acquisition Request" managing all the projects assignment and approvals.
- o Pentron website, allowing dentists to purchase and ship all their in-house products
- o DuoFast website, allowing contractors to purchase and ship hardware and tools.
- Developed an XML window service application that retrieves orders from Henry Schein, so products can be shipped from Pentron.

Software Architect/Web Developer

Raytel Medical Corporation - Windsor, CT - March 1999 to May 2000

Designed and implemented database-oriented web-based inventory, enrollment, testing applications connecting to the Informix databases where the Medic system resided.

• Implemented a window service via VB, AS400 Medical Management system and the Patients Monitor ECG/ EKG testing system.

Software Developer

Opti-Fashion, Inc - Valhalla, NY - November 1997 to February 1999

Designed and implemented Sales/Customer/Inventory multidimensional drilldown analysis systems and graphical presentations via Essbase, OLAP scripts, RPG, Microsoft Access, Visual Basic and PowerPoint.

Software Developer/Analyst

Barclays de Zoette Wedd - New York, NY - July 1991 to November 1997

Worked with project manager to architect and build a custom derivatives trading system and a ticket less trading interfaces that provided the traders to track on-line positions, weighted average rates and yield curves.

• Implemented a Sales & General Ledger multidimensional, drilldown analysis, reporting and graphical presentations via Essbase.

Software Developer/Analyst

John Hancock Clearing Corporation - New York, NY - April 1987 to July 1991

Worked with a team and developed parts of a custom Mortgage Backed Securities and Securities Lending Systems that automatically updated the Pending and Settlement data warehouse, including audit trail features.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Computer Science and Information Systems in Art

Saint John's University Jamaica - Jamaica, NY

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Technical Skills

Application Development

ASP.NET (2.0/3.5/4.0), VB .NET, C#.NET, ADO.NET, Visual Studio (2010/2012/2013), Framework (1.1/2.0/3.0/3.5/4.0/4.5), Python Scripting

Database Design and Development

AS400, SQL Server (2000/2005/2008/2012), Oracle 11.0, Stored Procedures, Functions, Views, Triggers, Database design, JQuery, Providers for data manipulation LINQ (Language Integrated Query).

• Content Management

SharePoint (2007, 2013), SharePoint Designer (2007/2013)

• Source Code and Project Management

Team Foundation Server 2012 (Agile, Visual Studio Scrum), MS Project (2010, 2013)

Reporting

SQL Reporting Services 2012, Crystal Reporting 2013

Operating Systems

Windows 7, Windows 8, Windows 8.1

Graphic Software

Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop, Flash MX, 3D Studio Max, AutoCAD/.Net Integration

Web Tools and Technology

Ajax, Ajax Toolkit and JavaScript, XAML, XML, XSL/T, IIS, Web Services, WCF Services, Window System Services, HTML, CSS, HTML5, COM Protocols, SSIS, Master Pages, Site Map, Web Forms, MVC

Version Control Tools

Visual Source Safe 6.0, Team Foundation Server (TFS)

• External Services Integration

Verisign/Pay Flow Pro, Authorize.Net, FedEx, DHL, UPS

Methodologies

Agile, OOPS (Object Oriented Programming Structure), OOAD (Object-oriented analysis and design), SOA (Service-oriented architecture), Design Patterns, SDLC (Software Development Life Cycle)

Desktop Software

MS Office 2013 (Word, Excel, PowerPoint and Access), Visio, Excel VBA, MS Project

• Performances Software

WANem 2.0 (Wide Area Network Emulator)